all right i think this is officially one
of our board meetings but i think
they're melding into each other
so today we were meeting to discuss our
individual visions and missions for
together tech
and see about creating a common one
so we're all working towards the same
thing for together tech i know we had a
document last week again my
my computer i can no longer copy and
paste things so i'm
trying to figure out workarounds with
other devices but if somebody wants to
put that up as a screen share
and uh we can i have mine written out on
the
very technological sticky note here
my vision and mission so any anyone
wants to start sharing theirs or i can
share mine
i can pull it up if no one else has
well you're pulling that up and sharing
it i can share just
the vision i have written here is
creating the tools slash
infrastructure needed for
self-sufficiency of individuals
to society
i guess i should have asked whether
we're doing mission revision first
perfect awesome
probably vision so was that your vision
yeah that was the vision
and then mission was other versions of
why i put like playing it creating new
ways
solo to cooperative basically the same
version
of what it was a year ago which is that
it needs to be fun what we're doing
whatever path we're doing to get there
diverse options and ways to get there
and
um whatever we're creating is
trustworthy to the masses
based on the fact that it was created
together so it was kind of values but
also mission
was fun diverse and trustworthy
cool uh i can i can
tackle next um but i think that sounds
good
by the way um i had several visions
uh kind of statements um
i think you suggested to start out with
the world so
a world where game b is more common than
game a now that's
awfully broad and probably too broad for
this project
um and actually i was starting to think
in doing these
that i got confused again on whether
we're doing it for just
so i think this is for together tech but
we also need to discuss that we need a
separate one
or combined for the um
the fundraising game a projects
right and and so maybe there's two but
one kind of is supersedes the other
uh so and i thought another way phrasing
is a a world where ideas that increase
omni when
solutions benefit from and contribute to
a commons of tools knowledge mentoring
and funding
it's very long and then i like that one
and then a little bit too technical for
a vision
statement but or too specific but a
world where 99.99
of people have a personal quality of
life score above 90 percent
and the person equality of a life score
is not defined yet
i just made that up but um
is some effect of kind of how they
measure happiness or satisfaction and
some of the things you
you take a look and you see whether your
life
would you say that you know over the
past year or so that that you are set
how satisfied are you in your life and
then
either look to see that go up but but i
was thinking in general have people say
you know
uh you know out of a whole
unit x unit 100 satisfied where are you
um and i'd say a majority of people
right now are probably below 50.
so that would be a huge improvement
anyway so those are three ideas i just
want to throw out
and then for a mission um
encourage and facilitate the following
benefits for omni-win
ideas so knowledge commons digital tools
software infrastructure
and then mentoring and fundraising so
that's a longer way of saying what that
second bullet point had in there
um yeah
so those were my ideas
cool i like those um mine i still
need to probably go through a couple
passes i'm trying to hash out the
wording so i just threw some stuff on a
page that i knew was in the right
direction
and tried to to wordsmith it a bit um
so my my vision the two that i have that
sort of
i think all along the ones of the others
are a world where important technologies
of all types
have a place for safe and proven
services funding etc
and then a world where omni wind
projects can meaningfully compete and
build products
um i do sort of like the middle one
of bentley's i think it gets a good
sort of it covers a lot of the stuff
that we're trying to
do um for the mission i had quite a few
here
um the one that i think requires a lot
of work but i think
sort of also gets the general point
across
is to behave like a multinational sort
of holding company corporation
aligned around core values so where
profit is important but it's not number
one
unlike a lot of the other companies that
it would be technically competing with
um and then to provide thought
leadership on appropriate topics so
things that those sort of projects
would need um to manage coach build or
uh
uh otherwise assist with relevant
technology projects
and then have it sort of split out into
the not for for profits it could be
anything important
and for profitable companies um a system
as necessary but really just
to sort of help either if they are still
on omni when great
but a lot of that would be focused on
hopefully trying to get some
funding forward together take itself
to offer funding options from a
transparent ethical organization
uh to manage a set of certifications to
match the various standards set by the
community
to provide the public with a list of
projects in certified or allied
organizations
and then a temporary one but important
nonetheless is to get started
which for the most part means to get
funded to get some sort of source
of funding to actually start doing some
of the stuff
if anyone wants um they could put their
stuff in the chat
i'll paste it in here so we can look at
all on the screen at the same time
if you want um or whatever you'd like to
do
and jubilee if you want to say yours
again i could type it in yeah i was like
how will that work there'll be so many
spelling and grammar errors if i type it
in
i just had creating the tools slash
infrastructure
needed for self-sufficiency of
individuals to society
so however big society is your your
village your
family to the whole meta creating the
tools and infrastructure
for self-suffi needed for
self-sufficiency
of your community is that what you had
because it was right my kid made
chocolate milk with chocolate pudding
mix and one needed me to try it
i need to see your face sorry oh we're
creating the tools in infrastructure
needed for self-sufficiency of
individuals to society
so empowering the individual empowering
the group empowering society
okay and i don't know
uh adria if you want to paste those in
the what you have
uh shouldn't certainly put my phone on
someone because i forgot to do that
so those were the two visions not
properly split apart
and then out the mission is
gonna be interesting to try to paste uh
you know kind of grab the
more important ones i think and
did matush have a vision in mission i'm
guessing
the grand vision is to bring post
scarcity
uh finally to the world
i wanted to keep it very short so post
scarcity is
the keyword here and i guess
yeah the the traditional phrasing for a
vision is to say it already exists
so and so bringing would be the mission
but
um a post-scarcity world i guess would
be it right
for that vision i didn't find a
good enough way to say uh post scarcity
as in
resources physical stuff and mindsets
of the people because these are two
things that are actually important and
they are not exactly the same
and for the mission uh pretty much what
it's what is already there
with one addition being
supporting and encouraging local
[Music]
not villages but local communities to
um arise and uh
exist and yeah something that mentions
local communities as
a very important thing for the future
i'm gonna be formatting this all day so
um yeah so how does that
so uh i guess we heard everyone who was
assigned homework
um how do people
feel about that i don't know open
discussion
there's nothing that was said that i
disagree with like nothing that's there
that i'm like that
is going to hurt what i had in mind um
which is good none of them contradict
each other and we all have a slightly
different spin
on what that like
best omni-wind future is right like
matush was post scarcity
i was like self-sufficiency um i liked
bentley's
99.99 of people and quality of life
scored
above 90. i like that even though it's
not measurable yet that it's measurable
it's something we would
have people themselves giving that
metric
and um seeing is it improving right are
we
actually getting there
none of my electronics are working let
me decline a call
um yeah
mission because mine weren't really
mission but i had the mission of um
like that it needs to be fun there needs
to be many different ways to go about it
and um that we trust it i mean
we might trust each other right but we
are not necessarily going to trust
somebody else coming in
or someone else coming is necessarily
going to trust us having easy ways for
trust to be built on projects
and with individuals is fun diverse and
trustworthy
that's just values really
yeah trust does seem like a really
important theme from sort of all sides
like both you know for people in the
organization to know that the
organization they're working with and
for
is trustworthy and sort of going in the
right direction as a project you can
ally yourself with you know an
organization that says hey
we're with them so if you have some
trust issues you can go see
all the stuff that being with them means
uh and then a consumer
to make it sort of obvious hey if
anybody is allied with
you know this group here's what that
means here's why you can trust it
yeah i'm always a little not sure if
trust is
specific enough because there are you
can have trust in something because you
have faith in it and you can have trust
in something because you don't
need to trust it because it's fully
transparent
um and i'd prefer the latter
yeah i mean when i say trust i it's a
sort of always break that down into
character and
competence for character you know it's
like you trust
them that they aren't going to be
sketchy and sort of have ulterior
motives
and then character like they're actually
able to do what you're trusting them to
do not just that they'd actually want to
and so it would need to be both sides of
that right it would be like the
character of
the the organization um you know that if
they say that they're not for profit you
know that it's omni win that they're
actually that
but then also they're able to go out
there and compete in the world and
actually go
toe-to-toe with the organizations that
will end up being their you know
their competition um and actually you
know being able to go
like that's where i think the funding
issue gets really weird is
it in a lot of ways it needs to behave
like a game a
sort of fairly aggressive company but
without profit being the number what
one motive like profits just to keep the
lights on but if
i think if it's not being for lack of a
better term
aggressive then it ends up losing out
yeah i guess i i think that you can be
competent and um
and have character and that's i think
that's still a separate
thing than whether you're being
transparent
right yeah so yeah i mean i think
transparency is kind of needed for both
sides
um welcome steve if you uh want to
contribute you can unmute just keep
yourself muted
in between sharing so that we don't hear
the background noise
i believe you should be able to unmute
yourself
if not type it in the box and i'll i'll
do that
uh yeah for the idea of profit
the other version and maybe there's many
different options but
you're either profit or purpose so if
you're in it for purpose
then your first is your mission right if
you're a transportation company it's
transportation if your
communication company it's communication
that all companies have
profit first but they have to do um
purpose enough to
to stay in business hopefully we're
flipping that we're doing purpose
to the biggest one and like yeah we have
to be profitable enough
in order to be able to stay in business
and and flipping
flipping that but what that is for each
individual project is going to be
different
is it you know in wikilection and reason
score is it helping people make sense
and with trustworthy information that
they can use how much is it being used
what would make it even better
i'm sorry okay
when it came to that i um sort of like
was trying to figure out
especially for me because i think it's
important to sort of say like
profit is important but you can't fall
into the same trap as
gamey companies and so i came up with
the sort of like the
the priority list where the acronym is
vip
number one is values which i think that
that that's something that is kind of
separate to mission
and vision it's like the specific the
list of things that will always be
trying to improve and always
um be taking into account so the values
are number one
and then next is improvement like
improving the world
and like improving things for people and
for the environment and for animals and
for everything else
and then third is profit whereas like to
be able to keep the lights on to be able
to you know act like a company
but never before the other two
so profit is a business variable instead
of the goal right the goal is
values and what we know but profit is
one of the variables
of the life of the company right and
it's important enough that like
because of course the more money the
organization has it can pay its staff
it can you know actually compete in the
world arena with the
the challenges it will eventually have
both in legal and otherwise
um yeah like that
and definitely open to ideas there but
that was sort of like i
was trying to figure out a way to sort
of say like hey it's
sort of of like with the part where it
needs to behave
like a multinational corporation
like in the ways you know that it's
outlying a bunch of sort of
similar products and and organizations
towards the same goal
but with the unique difference being
that goal isn't just making money
and while money is important it can't
come at the expense of the whole reason
that we're doing this because how was it
actually different from
a game a multinational corporation if
profit
sneaks into you know spot number one at
that point it's not because that
has the same issues with profit being
your sole motive
yeah and you meant um yeah i wonder if
there's a better word than
profit because like you mentioned paying
your salaries but that's not
profit true uh yeah
like in this case i guess likely revenue
although i do also mean profit because
at the end of the day if you have profit
above your expenses where
you know staff wages are an expense it's
also profits you say hey
you know we spent this much on
infrastructure this much on wages we
have
this much money left over now the
organization can grow it can
you know possibly acquire other
companies it can buy real estate if it
wants like
you've got a lot more options to be able
to go
and do things and actually be able to
compete in the world if you have profit
what bentley had said that 99.9 of
people have have a high quality of life
with that score of 90
if we're never profitable if we never
have a dollar of profit but that number
is continually going up that's a much
better metric than hey we have this
money that we could be using to make
people's lives better but we're not and
so making sure
there's going to be reasons to hold on
to money to make that better in the
future
and reasons to spend that now to make
life better currently
and it's is like it's keeping that in
in our metric as opposed to
oh well if we keep this and we have an
interest rate of five percent then that
means we have you know like
just in the monetary sense versus
the rest right i think part of it is
trying to
seek profit so that the company has some
options
right like but at the exact time for all
that thing of like not doing it at the
expense of the other thing so values are
always number one
the value is omni-win and the value is
improving lives for people
then your goal is always to make more
money than you're spending
but if you only ever you know stick to
your values and
improve the world and you don't make a
profit then that's fine
because you you stuck to your first two
but profit is still important
which is amazing and i i because i
didn't do the homework properly
i'm the only one who did values right so
the question is because even my three
values right that i
included fun diversity and
uh trust and trust what's first what
second one's third
right to me well trustworthiness is
pretty damn important
but if i'm not having fun i'm not gonna
be hanging out here right so
individually fun
is pretty important but only for making
things that are trustworthy and
diversity is about making sure
it's fun enough for most people right so
that's just my own values forget about
once we include our values and all of
everything else
what does it mean don't live those
values first and in what order because
whichever one we're maximizing for
like there's if we have the same value
we know which one's first and second and
third it's a lot easier to rank that
at the same time then we're getting into
utopian territory
of our maximizing for the top one or two
values
as opposed to we actually can have
different values
maximize for different ones and because
we are holding strong in that right
jubilee stands for trustworthiness
and and whatever those other fun and
diversity
and maybe adult stands for justice and
you know like there's
that we have those different values but
there's going to be conflict
in not having like arrange them
ourselves even right and not knowing
what our conflicts are in value
our values are in conflict right i think
there's also like
there's things that we like that we want
to have happen
like for it to be fun but i'm not sure
that that's a value and like things like
transparency
you need to be transparent but i think
you you sort of need to be transparent
all like
that touches all the aspects so that's
an avenue of how you can show that
you're living
your your values but to me the values
are the
the things that as you're trying to
improve the world you know just itself
and for people and all those things
and trying to make sure that you have
enough profit to keep the lights on and
you have some options
they're in that order for a reason
values are always number one so it's
something that like
you know omni win is i think and obvious
one i think we're all on
the same page where it's okay so
everything that we do has to be as omni
when as possible
yeah but then again there's you know
what i mean omni win for who for
trade-offs for there's not going to
always be i think there is something
about saying that each individual
project
has its own values that are transparent
and they're transparent in which is
their first their second and their third
because they have to be even if they're
not
fully living that out in the world right
we're going to try to have have
transparency is number one we're going
to try to do this
and as long as that's open and
transparent then people can chew
then there isn't an overarching
we need our value together text values
to be as open as possible
so that those projects can be as as
different as possible and see which ones
play out where do people want to be
where what works what it's like oh look
all the transparency ones flopped for
whatever reason even
though we really held that as a high
value why
why is that that the case and be able to
play in that
so we could leave it it's just values
are number one without necessarily
seeing what those values are
omni-win being the number one one but
even that is going to come up against
conflict
and trump to me that's right where
improvement
comes in because it can be hard to get
stuck in the perfection thing and
i'm always about progress over
perfection that was kind of what
improvement was about it's like trying
to take steps we can't get it perfect
but it's better than what it is now cool
if it's better like in the you know
it aligns with our values it might not
be perfect but it it's moving our values
forward
that's the most important thing like
when we're actually taking action
and i think you're right that projects
will have their own
their own values right like if if
wikilection and reason score right have
something around sense making
well odds are together tech probably
won't have that it'll
it will support projects that might have
varying
levels i think part of what the values
need to do is
identify who we don't work with like
what are
the the the things where we say hey this
project sounds interesting
but you know or possibly it's profitable
and it will help us keep keep lights on
but we aren't interested in working with
them because
you know they make their money through
this way and that violates our values so
no we can't work together
and that is i think one of the the
challenges of figuring out where
projects differ from
together tech i think in the long run
if we're if we're talking about the so
we have the two projects one is the
kind of i guess we'll call the funding
project maybe or something that project
that's used
to fund other projects to do game a to
fund game b
that one i think you might have profit
as a value
if it's the understanding that profit
means the funds that you send
to together tech but together tech
itself
um i don't think profit should be a
value
because all funds should be reinvested
yeah and that's what i like i fully
admit that profit is not the ideal world
the ideal word there the the end goal is
though that i think it needs to behave
like a profit-seeking company in a lot
of ways
so that it has extra money that i can
throw around
because in the end i would like it to
kind of be a co-op
venture capital fund where we can say
instead of just hey
wiki election reason score i'll throw
you know a little bit of money you're
you you're away for funding
if there's actually enough money you
know for example during
the pandemic when some businesses are
going under we can say hey
these ones sound interesting they align
with our values and they can help us you
know fund future projects
let's buy those companies so let's
let's for now change it it's a perfect
word but let's use revenue
because nothing you've said is profit
it's all
i just that by the definition of the
word
um i don't think people use the
definition the same way you have
um and to be clear we're doing this this
what we're doing is for together tech
not for the
the profit driven ones but it's good to
keep bringing them in here and our own
individual projects to see that
different umbrella right that that
that's part of having the value
structure it's very
profitability in that is the whole point
of your that purpose right that's why
you guys are kind of not necessarily
concentrating on
your real your real projects in order to
put some time and energy towards that
one so it's profitable in your own lives
and
possibly for together tech that's very
different but it's transparent
i mean it's like that's the purpose of
this project
is to do that when there's projects in
the future
that have like hey we're not making
enough money but this one is
a profit driven one it's going to drive
profit for the rest of them
and having it be possibly insulated in
that way so it is trying to make profit
for the rest of it but it's also being
fed with like we all still own it we are
still part of it and so we're not gonna
want it to be
uber profitable when it causes a
problem for the community right okay
well now we can't afford it
your guys is what you're doing is
different because it's not for the
community it's for
the outside
yeah so yeah it's it's um
uh yeah just separate them what would
you say kind of did you say an
accelerator
um incubator
um
great accelerate
i'm just want to write that down before
i forgot yeah
i think in a lot of ways that's kind of
the role that together tech is trying to
play is as
an incubator for kind of all the
different
yeah i guess the funding project is
still just to get the funding
and but the the yeah the um
yeah you're right so we just have one
goal
to provide funding for game v project i
mean there might be some other things
do without without ruining the world
right
how do you say harmlessly provide
so we are not going to ever have like
piracy division
in together a water division
piracy piracy division pirates are
pretty cool i don't know
what parents are like ah although um all
things considered they do
some harm to the you know world
sometimes
well yeah so i there i i would not rule
out the chance that there might be some
forms of piracy that is an omni win
but in general yeah and i think omni win
is always going to be a bit of a
misnomer because like there's people who
actively like
their goal is to be above others they
aren't going to win as a part of omni
win
well yes well they will be hurt by it
you could
say that that's giving them an
opportunity for mental growth
emotional growth or unless you're
benefiting them they're
being benefited in the group of everyone
they just don't get
benefited in the group of like person
who thinks they're better and should be
doing better off and have you know a
thousand times more well
like yeah well i mean yeah if they if
they come to an emotional breakdown and
realize that wealth was not a good goal
then
then they benefited but yeah uh yeah
yeah we we won't unfortunately full omni
win is not
is probably not an achievable goal but
as much as possible
cool yeah i think the a big part of this
is figuring out what together tech
itself
is because that's a big part of like
the marketing for these different
profitable like
funding projects a part of how they'll
be marketed
is hey x percent of our profit goes
towards this
thing um
which you know may or may not end up
being important but like it is an
important aspect of the project that
would probably be at you know at the
very least get a prominent spot on the
website
not necessarily be in all of the
marketing materials but like
that would be one of the unique aspects
and i think like if the
like you know the cooperative enterprise
takes off you might end up with other
projects wanting to do similar things
where you know it might not be the same
percentage
but honestly if a for-profit project
that wasn't harmful wanted to give us 10
percent of their
profit cool still money still going to
help if we had you know
more of them and then i think that in
the end together tech ends up providing
a list of hey here's
the projects that we're either working
with as you know
we own them or we're just working
together or
they're actually helping fund us they
don't own us
but they're helping to you know fund
some money and here's the amount of
profit that they're giving that sort of
thing to sort of say
like to offer just a basic list on
here's the companies that if you're
wanting to support us
you can support them and that does help
us yeah
i wonder if now would be a good time for
us to kind of narrow down and
choose a vision because we could get
bogged down in the mission
um right totally um
uh so
i like this concept but i don't like the
way it's sorted the
a world where 99 percent of people
because vision statements
aren't intended to be kind of numerical
and
yeah i feel like that's maybe a mission
that's like
one of the missions is to provide a
quality of life score above 90
to 99.99 of people yeah i mean the the
only real difference between the mission
and vision is
whether it's past tense or future times
um yeah so we could but
but i but i like the idea and
um i i was thinking about a
post-scarcity world
is good and short i'm just wondering
does post-scarcity um
say what we want to accomplish
like i don't know if it's possible but
let's say we had a post-scarcity world
where people were still unhappy for
another reason right would that be
something we'd want
like people will always be unhappy about
some reason or another
and some people are going to be unhappy
about
not having the original of mona lisa
let me let me be clear a majority of
people are majority of the time
unhappy which probably isn't even today
so i'm just saying that
that it doesn't take i don't know that
that statement takes into account
i mean what's it matter having post
scarcity if everyone is miserable every
minute of every day
right which may not be possible because
you're saying
your mindset is post-scarcity as well
but i'm just saying that
scarcity still seems it's a it's a means
to an end
what's the end as opposed to the means
unless it is an
end are you wrong uh and i don't have it
with me right now or maybe i will um
something along the lines of uh postcard
post scarcity uh
meaning exactly uh that people do not
have to
worry about basic necessities like food
water
shelter and the basic stuff
and that way what it's going to cause is
it's going to
release uh the time energy and
creativity of the people who
no longer have to spend like
eight hours a day uh
working to just get the basics
like food and shelter i guess it depends
on what you include in basics
because if you include
yeah i guess i could still see a world
where you could include the basics but
it'd still be a pretty crappy world
another so i'm not sure if that's the
vision we want
i think yeah i think getting into
post-scarcity also has the same issue
that like anti-rivalrous
and anti whatever the other one is right
brazil
like that it's against something it's
like scarcity and then we got past it as
opposed to
there's a a big quality of post scarcity
that we can be living now in fact we are
living it with these meetings right
there
is already omni win because it's like
right if you succeed as much as it might
feel like that costs me something it
doesn't actually cost me something
it's benefiting me and so we're already
learning that
post-scarcity mindset within a scarce
world
that there is something
right what we're looking for is that um
and i
forget what the word is bentley you've
used it before of like
abundance abundance is not
uh like it's not happiness it's
something else satisfaction
satisfaction like that people are
satisfied with their life
and not in a way that we can gain not in
a way where it's like
oh we're just gonna add five points to
that because we want our numbers to go
up this year right
like in a way that it's like no are you
more satisfied than last year
what would make you even more satisfied
i can't imagine like my utopian vision
of a world
we live it now i'm like well i don't
even know what to look like in a year
how would i be more satisfied than this
whereas post-scarcity isn't because it's
like you get there and then you
arrived as opposed to we can live it now
and it's always improving and
satisfaction is kind of that thing
you can't be satisfied if your life
isn't like at least a little bit getting
better or you're getting more
deeperly satisfied with what you do have
but it's like a
personal thing so even shorter way of
saying this
though it's also more vague
is replacing motivation of the people
uh from currently in the
world of scarcity it's fear mostly
uh fear and oppression and violence
built within this uh the system we have
so replacing fear with for the lack of
better no actually that's the best word
uh
fear with love love is the thing that
signifies openness and um doing stuff
voluntarily
and um not being
forced to do stuff just the you know
opposition
the current system is sphere based and
the system you want
uh is love based basically
i love it because it is so simple and
yet we can't
erase it all we'll just put love for our
vision and it's like so true
and also been co-opted so much that it
doesn't work then when you try to define
it
and you know make the details
uh more explicit that's that's kind of
difficult
but still post scarcity means you don't
have to fear
that next day you are not going to have
a shelter over your head because uh
a bank will take it or you don't have
food because you don't earn enough or
stuff like that
yeah i like that i like where it's going
um and these things don't have to change
but just to note a few things we're
still talking about what it
isn't and then i have a concern with the
word love because i don't think if you
talk to the average person on the street
they would say that love is open
um just because it's understood never
used words
yeah i think confusing i think we also
might be trying to like encompass
everything whereas i think a lot of the
problems will actually be solved
will be solved by the underlying
projects and really we're trying to
empower projects to be able to make the
meaningful changes in the world that
they're trying to so yeah we could go
back to
this item two where the this things is
just to make sure that the omni win
solutions
and we could not use omni-win but
whatever these projects are
are happening and that's the vision and
not
that we actually achieve the game that's
the one that i like
the most because i think that's true
that's the truest to what together tech
is trying to do
and then like if together tech you know
helps enable wikilection and
and reason score and um we're getting
the name of
matushes uh hyperlocals
thank you and all these other projects
they'll each have their own vision and
their own mission
that i think you know will hopefully
help enable a post-scarce
scarcity world and increase satisfaction
all these things but that's
up to those all that that we're sort of
doing is helping
align all those projects to be like we
want you to succeed or fail based on
your project itself and not because the
world isn't set up
for your kind of a not-for-profit
omni-win you know community-based
project
yeah i like it because it also like what
we said about values earlier right like
it's like your
individual project can pass can fail can
try new things can have fun can be a
fascist or
maybe not fascist but you know like you
could you can play within that
and but together tech is here to have
the arena here to do
the the coordination between the
projects and then yes we might figure
out a way to also create them ourselves
but
you just adding to this we just said we
can take everything else away
i'm just re i'm just rephrasing it uh
yeah i i think that's good the um
the problem is that we're we're
mentioning omni one in here
or yeah things like omni win game b i
think that's the sticking point i think
the second one is the closest but
there's that key
thing that we still have to define
whether it's game b or omni win or you
know
world changing or whatever phrase we're
i think that's really the because then
we'll put love in there which was our
other problem
um which might be the solution but also
the interesting thing about using game b
rather than the other terms is it
is still very nebulous and we could use
it as a placeholder and replace it later
yeah um
yeah i like it because it also it kind
of encompasses exactly what we're saying
like if you know there's
12 values that an ideal organization has
but you have 10 of those values or you
have three of those values really really
strongly that's more game b than what we
got going on
and so it's more omni-win and it's more
in that direction and that's
so i wonder if then the vision just
mentions the values like if it's like
you know to help support
projects that move the you know
together tech values forward in a
meaningful way or something
like that and then as we hash out the
list of values because that's really i
think what it's all about if omni 1 ends
up being a value
cool then that's one of the things that
we're always trying to improve
there's i and if the evolve is using
can be just because it's a nebulous and
like hotly contested
and i don't even want that to be a part
of the conversation we're trying to have
like our own
version of what we think game b might be
but knowing that like
people in game b won't like that we're
using that label because well it's
omni-win but it's not this particular
kind of omni one that was in this
podcast
how if we just say blank that's probably
the most honest thing
that we can do right now which is what
game b stands for
so there is like there's
it is exactly that as long as we're not
saying our version is the one and only
game b
it is game b it's like game b projects
omni wind having the
project aligned with our values
that way we don't have to define what it
is
we'll put b ish blank flash game b
and we could find this later are we are
we
good with this um
i mean i kind of like the last half of
yours where it's more specific
whereas like we're able to benefit from
and contribute to a comment of tools
knowledge measuring and
and and funding because i mean that's
pretty encompassing
yeah it's enough that it's just kind of
longer than you want a vision statement
to be
is it right but if we have that in the
mission i think
yeah i mean i i like that i think it
still needs some
finagling but overall that's by far the
closest that we've seen
what do you think my douche is it too
far away from your vision
no it's it's fine i don't
um it's good
i was just thinking about it uh
game
and uh no people in game b
won't object to us uh
[Music]
using this uh too much because after all
we are game b
as well so we are two grain b people
my only concern is that we're because
we're actually trying to like
have you know effectively an
organization
we're gonna kind of having to start
almost you know
carving things in stone not actually
stone but like actually putting pen to
paper and saying these are the values
that we're going to operate
and just as soon as you connect these
values to game b
in my experience there's some
disagreement on like oh well that's not
game d well that's kind of game b but
not game b
enough that's what uh
beauty of it all though is that it's
nebulous and that you can't quite
pin it down and yet other people are
like that's not game b this is game b
is the beauty of it the only thing you
need to be indoctrinated into
the only thing jubilee not to to
adriel's point
although i don't i don't think it's a
stopping point at this point is that
once we start we're gonna have to
solidify it some um
and that's that's when the game be um
yeah no no i i i i i think that that is
you can't say that's what it is
it gave me is like omni-win infinite
game
and so if it's if it's more omni-win
and more infinite so therefore it uses
the resources more in alignment with
what nature does and more people win
from it then it's closer to game b than
game a
but is it easier to say game b or to say
omni win and infinite
and are those the things because just
like with the values we might agree that
values are important
but not which value is the highest
that's this the
everyone has a slightly different
version of game b is game b
like it's like right we don't need to
have one foundational these are all the
values and they're in this order
it's about everyone having a different
beautiful future that is omni-win
my omni win play my game my way please
if we're talking about values i wonder
if we just kind of switch the order and
it's like
a world where abundant resources are
available to projects that align with
our values
because like this all whether it's game
b or omni winner this
we need to define that list of values
and that's what everything is based on
like that sort of whether it's game b or
not and whether or not some people agree
if that's game b or not or or game b
enough like all that we're really saying
is that this is our take on like
here's what game b could be we aren't
saying it is
because you know we yeah there's totally
a possibility that we're wrong and that
omni when
we have a slight a slightly different
version of it
in the end that we're always like what
this group decides on the values are
that's what's going to drive everything
at some point i'm going to propose not
using game v but rather
more uh super set of game b is
non-game a and that's
they're not going to they can't object
to that right
well yeah the the only problem is then
we're we're also defining by what it
isn't
but that's not that's a small knit um
so if we're trying like the the wording
that i think might make sense is
a world where abundant resources are
available oh that's what you said
two projects and then we can decide how
to word it there but i think it's like
two projects that align with
together tech values or our values or
however you want to phrase it
but to be serious omni-winners for me is
the
the best description same here if i had
to pick a term i'd pick on me one
but i i do sort of like keeping it
somewhat open so that
the value list that we can just tweak
that as we go and i think the omni one
is going to be
quite possibly the number one value or
at least you know highly
rep represented with whatever words end
up being used
but
so let's let's use that
sure i'm comfortable with that um we'll
just italicize it to say
and by the way actually the link the
definition we
we really have to have a talk about
terminology at some point in this
group the definition for omni-win
is not useful
or at least the one the one on the game
b library
um or anything i've ever heard anyone
say except for the words omni-win
actually mean it unless you don't know
what the word omni means
okay so when we explain it i think it's
just any process
to where every being
wins there's benefits and not even human
we can decide whether it's human or just
just just human or
animals and that's why you say being i
saw a great definition somewhere
but i was actually kind of disappointed
at this
um that's so that's my rant for today
welcome to bentley's rants yeah i do
definitely agree that at some point
even like if we're sort of intentionally
taking a step
outside of game b saying like when we
say omni and here's what we mean for the
purposes of this project
just because yeah i think it's important
to have some sort of an
aligned thing and i agree that it
shouldn't only be humans animals just
the environment itself
however it's going to be all sentient
beings to look after animals if we're
also eating non-vegan and you know and
doing
doing those like are we left of a food
delivery
place that's offering eggs and milk
because that's not looking it's
definitely not omni went into the
chicken and cows right
but like it it is if they have a better
life than they would otherwise right
if it's free range that's absolutely
an improvement i think this is you know
progress over
perfection and that is part of it though
right is well
um like is a horrible chicken's life
worth more than zero chickens lives
because
is it bad you know like is bad chicken
prison worse than not being alive at all
and like we have to decide for the
chickens and anyway
let's have it there for all beans but
also maybe we could make it clear that
human beings have to be the first ones
because
like i would love the world to be vegan
it's not happening
i don't even want to be vegan there's
like
that's that's not like humans need to
feel like they're cared for and
have abundant lives before they can ever
think of getting there and so it's like
you
even if you care about animals the
planet humans being first is getting
there but
yeah i think a lot of that just comes
down to the like not increasing harm
yeah i think that
seeking perfection because i mean it's
the same thing like
if we end up doing business with a group
that has you know it's improved it but
it still has slavery right like it's cut
the
number of slaves needed by 90 percent
well but they're still slaves okay yeah
but it's a 90 improvement
what do we do there i personally would
say go ahead because that's an
improvement you know
the 90 percent of slaves you just freed
the world's better for them that's
yeah yeah that improvement but still
technically bad for
you know the 10 still there
i think the same thing with you know
animals and all that it's just like
you have your values and you're always
trying to move towards improvement
yeah so that's so next i need to come up
with a definition for romney one and i
put pro on the win just to give us
an out the b down the street doesn't
benefit from your project
so i'm not gonna fund it um
or the flies that i killed in the fly
trap today that's not very nice
um anyways
so yeah i think um i like that
and then we can we can workshop this bit
a little bit more
um says our vision
it's definitely what we're looking to do
is create
abundant resources for our projects for
us
yeah we are our projects at the moment
but yeah
yeah and that works because that does
sort of like help with all the different
levels that
i think we'd like to end up doing to
start with it can just be hey we're just
you know providing thought leadership
and then it might end up being like okay
we're actually you know giving you
certifications to
say you know a quick here's how
transparent we are here's how ethical
our production lines are that sort of
thing
and eventually possibly actually owns
some projects
and all of those i think are
encapsulated by
abundant resources being available uh
but
matush do you want to be one of the
official signatories or do you want to
be a
participant uh
i want to sign this why not okay i think
the
sticking point there was like you know
being able to commit to
eight hours so assuming that you can do
that and all the meetings yeah yeah
yeah like the point is that if you
couldn't attend we'd reschedule
it does this unfortunate
thing uh with my facebook account not
being originally
uh like totally mine
and i need to officially change my
matrix name to something
that is more official so that's the one
i just
typed in which is of course much
[Music]
less convenient but still that's
official name so
it can be my official name in the and i
have to say
it's great that our vision is so
ideology
yeah yes uh so modest
and you know so
can we use your official first name or
do you
what do you like to be called
uh usually it's uh
like official name is good and it's
radic the short form
and much it was reserved only for
facebook
for some uh ancient purpose
so so we could so if we called you radic
that would be closer than much
oh definitely okay there's a
long story behind this but uh yeah
rather this
is perfect
you are i officially named it i like it
my personal role is you only have one
name and you
show it everywhere although facebook
does have
they do have a limiting thing to where
you're supposed to use your full legal
name
um so that's a pain
yeah it started the facebook account as
something actually i
use much only uh in a very few places
because of uh historical
uh reasons but i need to clean this up
at some point and yeah as well i may
start right now
all right we're close to the hour do we
want to get homework for
next week like do this again or does
this not work for what we
it might not work for our next part like
are we going to go over mission next
week
in which case we have it here i think i
think yeah let's
let's hit mission next week and then
everyone kind of think about the vision
we can change it if if you have
something passionate to bring up
we are not a heavy rules-based
group um
so so yeah then then um i can
i don't know if everyone has this link i
can send it out and um
and then just look at these mission
ideas and and we'll
chat and see if we can come to an
agreement next week yeah i think it'll
definitely help sort of having the the
vision defined to help them
steer our mission in that direction it's
true
not everything omni went all at once but
the tools the umbrella
or all the other things yeah i think
that helps
uh and uh steve was asking about the
dock it is open for anyone to
comment um
uh or maybe i may have shared it let's
check the sharing settings live
on video um i may i think it's set to
where anyone can edit it
but if not it you can put comments on
there and i'll add it in just
every once while someone deletes
everything but there's a full history so
i really don't have an excuse
only people added can open this link
yeah i'm fine with only having
read-only access to it and then i'll be
putting stuff into my now you know what
let's make it
well this video is going out and i don't
want the link everywhere
let's um we we can do it after we
stop going live yeah
anyway so yeah i will i will figure that
out and uh yeah we'll get something that
everyone can
edit and play around with but even if
you just brainstorm on a separate sheet
and bring it together
depends whether you want other people to
to see it and have
impressions before you talk about it
yeah and i'm not against like you know
split out meetings in between now and
then just like i mean there's a good
chance that julie and i will
we'll we'll connect offline and sort of
chat about this so
it's also good to admit that that can
happen in you know any direction
and for the most part we're trying to
follow the protocol.love like
raymond's recommendation and sort of how
to go about this where it's like sort of
mainly meant to be though these these
signatories
who need to come into a full agreement
but they're still the participants who
i mean if they have a good idea is a
good idea it doesn't matter where it
comes from
and i think it also helps people who
aren't quite as you know like fully
involved showing up to
most or all of these sessions seeing
what they think together tech is
currently sort of doing and standing for
and what they think makes sense with
what they believe together tech to be
with what they've seen so far
yeah and there's a question
sorry go bentley there's a question
about whether it's there's room for
discussion because it's the protocol
love eighth practice exercise
we haven't started the protocol love
exercise so everything's up for
discussion and even after that we're an
open group so
everything's always up for discussion if
you can
make someone listen to you if you're
really boring maybe not
yeah you're on your own there but get
more exciting
and then you can save the world
step one that's our mission does anyone
add that to the mission get more
exciting
then people will care that we're trying
to save the world
[Music]
all right so by next week we will have
looked at the mission someone can send
me the link
i can look at it at my other computer
and just
i'm going to look at them and decide
somewhat what the order is
are they relevant to our actual vision
now and then what the order i think they
should be in
and then come to it with that so that
i'm not what's the word
coerced by all of your fine opinions i
will come in already with my ideas
no budging that's the that's right
number one
yeah but see seeing the averages seeing
where they roll out with
all of us all right uh we're here
tomorrow morning our time i can't do
that math
9 a.m civic standard time for our round
tables so we tell you what our project
individual projects are
welcome to join and we help each other
in whatever way we can
sorry quick note there's a facebook post
about joining
the crowdsourced
um matching system discussion
so if anyone wants to to
participate in the doodle on choosing a
time find that post on facebook
sorry then that's it thank you
goodbye to youtube and facebook see you
tomorrow morning